America was born in the streets.
Gangs of New York is a drama, history, crime film directed by Martin Scorsese.
In early 1860s New York, Irish immigrant Amsterdam Vallon is released from prison and returns to the Five Points,
seeking revenge against his father's killer, William Cutting, a powerful anti-immigrant gang leader.
He knows that revenge can only be attained by
infiltrating Cutting's inner circle.
Vallon's journey becomes a fight for personal survival
and to find a place for the Irish people.
Amsterdam Vallon, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Bill 'The Butcher' Cutting, played by Daniel Day-Lewis.
Jenny Everdeane, played by Cameron Diaz.
Boss Tweed, played by Jim Broadbent.
Happy Jack, played by John C. Reilly.
Johnny Sirocco, played by Henry Thomas.
Gangs of New York is a 2002 epic historical drama film directed by Martin Scorsese and written by Jay Cocks,
Steven Zaillian, and Kenneth Lonergan, based on Herbert Asbury's 1928 book The Gangs of New York.
The film stars  Daniel Day-Lewis, Leonardo DiCaprio, and
Cameron Diaz, along with Jim Broadbent, John C.
Reilly, Henry Thomas and Brendan Gleeson in supporting roles.
The film also marks the start of a collaboration between DiCaprio and Scorsese.
The film is set from 1862 to 1863, when a long-running Catholic–Protestant feud erupts into violence, just
as an Irish immigrant group is protesting the threat of conscription during the Civil War.
Scorsese spent 20 years developing the project until
Miramax Films acquired it in 1999.
Principal photography took place in Cinecittà Studios in
Rome, and Long Island City, New York City.
Gangs of New York was completed by 2001 but its release was
delayed due to the September 11 attacks.
The film was theatrically released in the United States on
December 20, 2002, and grossed $193.8 million worldwide.
It was met with generally positive reviews, and
Day-Lewis's performance was highly acclaimed.
It received 10 nominations at the 75th Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director
for Scorsese and Best Actor for Day-Lewis, but did not win in any category.
The film explores themes of rescue, immigrant, ship, fire, army.
The tone is emotional.